techpapers.com 2015-03-15

# TechPapers | White Papers for IT Professionals

###### Privacy Policy

This privacy policy discloses the privacy practices for TechPapers®.

A Special Note About Children: Persons under the age of 18 are not eligible for any offers presented by TechPapers®.

Registration: We request information from you on our subscription forms. This information is used for order fulfillment, customer service and to understand your areas of interest. We send this information to the publishers of the content you request.

Tracking Technology: If you have been offered our services through one of our marketing partners or affiliates (see “Use of Information” section below), we may share the information you enter with that partner or affiliate. To do so, we may use a technology called clear GIFs, which automatically and securely transfer the information you enter. In the future, we may also use other similar technologies in our offers for the same purpose. If we do so, we will modify our privacy policy accordingly. See the “Notification of Changes” section below.

Log Files: We log IP addresses (a unique number assigned to every computer on the Internet) in order to improve security, analyze trends and administer our offers. We may track your movement within our sites, the pages from which you were referred, access times and browser types. We only use this information in aggregate and do not link it to you personally.

**Use of Information**

Contractual Relationships

We provide your information to, and make it available to, our third party service vendors with whom we have contractual relationships for the purpose of servicing and processing of your magazine subscriptions. These vendors provide various services on our behalf such as customer service and web hosting. These vendors are not allowed to sell, rent or lease your personally identifiable information and are not permitted to use your information for any secondary purpose.

Content Publishers

When you request content, we forward your contact and address information to the applicable content publisher to determine your eligibility for fulfillment. The publishers of the content you have chosen to receive may use the information you provided to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies. When requesting content, we encourage you to read the privacy statement of the publisher of such content; we do not review the privacy policies of the publishers in our program and are not responsible for their actions.

Retailers/Special Offers

When you choose to accept a special retail offer, we forward your contact information to the applicable retailer and/or sponsor for fulfillment. The retailers and/or sponsors for the offers you have chosen to receive may use the information you provided to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies.

Third Party Marketing Affiliates

If you accept one of our offers by linking through one of our partners or affiliates, your information also may be shared with the partner or affiliate which originated the link to our site. These partners and affiliates may use the information you provided to present you with other opportunities in accordance with their own privacy policies. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of our partners and affiliates.

Exceptional Circumstances

Please note that if TechPapers® or any of M2 Media Group business lines is sold or disposed of as a going concern, whether by merger, sale of assets or otherwise, the relevant customer database of M2 Media Group could, in whole or in part, be sold as part of that transaction. We also may have to release personally identifying information when it is necessary to comply with judicial or other government subpoenas, warrants or orders.

Links

Content offers may contain links to other sites. Please be aware that M2 Media Group is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of each web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by M2 Media Group.

Security

M2 Media Group takes measures to protect the personal information you enter by using Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption, which is recognized as an industry standard in encryption technology, whenever you enter personal information. 

Special Offers and Choice/Opt-out

After you complete our registration and subscription forms, your answers and contact information are sent to the publisher of the content you requested so they can determine your eligibility and fulfill your requested content. These publishers may also contact you with special offers. From time to time, we may present you with specially selected offers from M2 Media Group or one of our partners. Out of respect for your privacy, you can forfeit any of these opportunities by sending an email [question@techpapers.com](mailto:question@techpapers.com) requesting to opt-out of future offers. 

Site and Service Updates

We communicate with you to provide requested services and on issues relating to your content. We also send site and content service updates. You are not able to unsubscribe from these important announcements, which contain important information about your content and M2 Media Group.

Correcting/Updating Personal Information

If you want to change any personal information you previously provided to us (such as your address) you can do so by emailing us at [question@techpapers.com](mailto:question@techpapers.com).

Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our site by identifying them as changes to our previous privacy policy. We will identify those changes for at least 60 days so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

Information Collection and Use

M2 Media Group is the owner of the information collected on this site. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please email us at [question@techpapers.com](mailto:question@techpapers.com).
